<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AlpsCode</title><link>https://alpscode.com/</link><description>Recent content on AlpsCode</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alpscode.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Friendly Introduction to FPL Analytics</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/intro-to-fpl-analytics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/intro-to-fpl-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>In this post, I tried to summarize the basics about using analytical tools and methods for Fantasy Premier League (FPL).
There is certainly more out there than I can cover, but I hope this will help newcomers to understand what analytics is and how it can help you enjoy FPL more.
Similar ideas can be applied to other fantasy sports games as well.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="part-1-seeing-beyond-the-curtain-underlying-stats">Part 1: Seeing Beyond the Curtain &lt;em>(Underlying Stats)&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You are sitting on your couch on a Saturday morning and suddenly remember that you have to transfer someone for your FPL team to beat your friend in &lt;em>that&lt;/em> mini-league.
You open the FPL app, sort players by total points so far and transfer the player on top that you do not own!
You are not 100% sure how the points system works in FPL, but after all, past performance should be an indicator of future performance, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflections from my first FPL season</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-reflections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-reflections/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you ask any Fantasy Premier League (FPL) player on Twitter about what word has been beaten to death last season, they&amp;rsquo;d likely respond with &amp;ldquo;optimal&amp;rdquo;.
I must admit that I played a part in starting or fuelling more than my fair share of these discussions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">There are optimal ways to play FPL.&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Sertalp B. Çay (@sertalpbilal) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sertalpbilal/status/1376578600854519808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 29, 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>


&lt;p>It might come as a suprise to some that I had never heard of FPL before August of 2020, just a week before I went on vacation.
It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that my time off was spoiled (to a degree) after my dear colleague, Bas Belfi, challenged me in the upcoming FPL season with the aid of analytics.
Like any sane person, I spent most of my time after that reading through rules, reviewing academic papers, and taking notes from every guide I came across on Reddit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rocket League as a Sports Analytics Sandbox</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/rocket-league-and-sports-analytics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/rocket-league-and-sports-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Taking a serious interest in sports analytics was probably the best thing I did during the pandemic.
Not only is it fun to play with and analyze, but it&amp;rsquo;s also easy to make connections with ongoing events while also providing you with a broader understanding of the sports.
There are, however, a few roadblocks.
Reaching to the data, especially on-pitch data, is very difficult.
You can find summarized stats but more granular specifics such as tracking data is treated as a premium commodity and understandably so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hindsight Optimization for FPL</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/hindsight-optimization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/hindsight-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p>This season certainly proved how random FPL could get, full of difficult decisions and regret.
Every GW, we&amp;rsquo;d look at our team and wish that we&amp;rsquo;d that shiny player everyone else had.
Sometimes Bruno, sometimes Gundogan, and sometimes Martinez.
Week after week we were filled with regret after not buying (or worse: benching) that player.
Of course with hindsight being 20/20, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see what you missed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what if you could get the &lt;a target=_blank href="https://youtu.be/zorz3SXqjv0">&amp;lsquo;Almanac&amp;rsquo; just like in Back to the Future 2&lt;/a> and know how every week would play out?
You might think it could make your life easier, but that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely correct.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Optimization Modeling for Expected Threat</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/expected_threat_optimization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 21:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/expected_threat_optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you know little about football analytics, I can safely assume that you have heard of expected goals (xG).
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, xG is a metric showing the probability of a shot to be successful with the information we have, such as position, body part, and defender positions.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
Another of such metrics is expected assists (xA) which can measure the probability that a pass leads to a goal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>O-Ring Optimization for FPL</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/o-ring-optimization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/o-ring-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Numbers Game&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> is a great read for anyone interested in football (soccer) analytics.
The book covers a wide range of events where numbers give insights to football professionals on topics like possession, short/long passes, and team evaluation.
I have recently read the section about the &amp;ldquo;O-Ring theory&amp;rdquo;, which brought a couple of new ideas regarding FPL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>O-Ring theory&lt;/em> says that a team (or a system) is as strong as its weakest link.
The idea itself is coming from the Space Shuttle &lt;em>Challenger&lt;/em>, where the failure of O-ring seals caused the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_Shuttle_Challenger_disaster" target="_blank">catastrophic event in 1986&lt;/a>.
When applied to football, the theory points out that clubs should be improving (or replacing) their weakest players in the field, instead of focusing on superstars.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the meaning of optimal in FPL</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/optimal-in-fpl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/optimal-in-fpl/</guid><description>&lt;p>The amount of available content for Fantasy Premier League (FPL) is unbelivable and hard to follow.
Among all, one of my favorite resources is the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/uncertainty_pod" target="_blank">Corridor of Uncertainty&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; podcast as they focus on modeling and analytics part of FPL.
Their guest in the latest episode was Abdul Rehman (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FPL_Salah" target="_blank">FPL Salah&lt;/a>), who is a well-known manager in the FPL community.
I truly enjoyed their discussion and noticed that the word &amp;ldquo;optimal&amp;rdquo; is thrown around quite a bit.
Since I do optimization for a living, it makes me happy to hear it in everyday conversations, especially regarding FPL.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On FPL, Optimization, and Ownership Weights</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-ownership-weight/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-ownership-weight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Cialdini mentions &lt;em>scarcity&lt;/em> as one of the 6 principles of persuasion.
The nature of seeking something of great interest is embedded inside all of us.
Our first reaction when we see other people do something is to follow them.
Even though it does not make too much sense, we follow the herd even in a competitive game, like Fantasy Premier League.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week&amp;rsquo;s (GW11) unfortunate gold rush to Jota proved that we fear being left out.
Of course the potential price changes further trigger and support our knee-jerk reactions, however it is important to separate what we want to do and &lt;strong>feel forced&lt;/strong> to do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notes from FPL Gameweek 2 and Optimization</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-notes-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 19:13:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-notes-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am playing Fantasy Premier League this seasons for the first time and I can already tell you that it is frustrating, despite using a mathematical model.
Even though I put no manual input of my own (all decisions are up to the mathematical model), I am watching almost all EPL games to improve the model and I can say that it is very addictive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growing up, I never liked watching live sports that much.
Many people find football (soccer) very boring, and I always had similar ideas except big tournaments like World Cup or important games.
To be honest, I never expected FPL to change my view this much.
The pure enjoyment and excitement to see the outcome of my mathematical model is something else; it is strong enough to wake me up at 7 am on weekends to catch games between teams I have never watched before.
Amazing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plotting a piecewise function graph in LaTeX</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/piecewise-latex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 14:09:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/piecewise-latex/</guid><description>&lt;p>I absolutely adore LaTeX generated documents and personally use it pretty much for anything I can.
Plotting graphs is one of my favorite thing to do.
TikZ library makes it quite easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To plot a piecewise function, I happened to learn about &lt;code>\tikzmath&lt;/code> which I have never used before.
Using it, you can define values and also perform math operations.
I used this approach to set values and plot the graph dynamically.
This approach saved me quite some to fine tune the graph in the long run.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What to do for a better password security and management</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/what-to-do-for-password-security/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 21:22:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/what-to-do-for-password-security/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know that much about cyber, but I do think that&amp;rsquo;s the number one problem with mankind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Warren Buffett&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We should be talking about password safety after &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/collection-one-breach-email-accounts-passwords/" title="Wired&amp;#39;s story on the issue" target="_blank">773 million records exposed&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who complain when IT forces to change passwords at regular intervals.
It is a nightmare for me to come up with secure passwords and even when I can, I have a hard time remembering them.
So, believe me when I say that I know the struggle of dealing with passwords.
My colleagues are the same.
Last week one of my colleagues was saying that &amp;ldquo;Ah damn, I got that password change notification again&amp;rdquo;.
Passwords are unfortunately a burden we need to carry, an artifact of the technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Linux on Windows</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/linux-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:30:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/linux-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>Linux is arguably the most developer-friendly operating system.
From automation to feature-rich text editors, I see Linux as a must for any programmer.
Powerful and hackable Linux ecosystem and the huge community make finding solutions to common problems very trivial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need to use Windows for a variety of reasons, you are not out of options when it comes to using Linux.
Over the years, I have tried a lot of different ways to enable Linux functionality on Windows, some are better than others but all of them have specific use cases.
Windows 10 started supporting Linux subsystem natively a while ago which is called Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL).
WSL basically enables you to run Linux executables on Windows 10, natively.
In this blog post, I will show how you can enable the Linux subsystem support on Windows 10, install Ubuntu and do some customization without an arm and a leg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing scripts with Reddit API</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/scripting-with-reddit-api/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 20:08:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/scripting-with-reddit-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post, I will show how you can use Python to gather content and create a simple web page around it.
See &lt;a href="https://alpscode.com/blog/how-to-use-reddit-api/">the first part&lt;/a> to learn how to register an app to Reddit API and get started.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="setup">Setup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I often use PyCharm or Jupyter notebook for Python, but any Python environment will do the trick.
You need to have a Reddit app id and app secret already at hand for this part.
A basic knowledge of HTML and CSS might be useful, but not required for the high level content.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to use Reddit API</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/how-to-use-reddit-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 23:28:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/how-to-use-reddit-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most valuable things I learned in recent years was learning how to use Public APIs to develop tools.
An API (Application program interface) is a set of tools to communicate with another service.
Learning how to use APIs is very valuable for web applications, but beyond that it is a useful skill to expand your horizon.
Once you get the hang of it, there is endless possibilities what you can do with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://alpscode.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="about">About&lt;/h1>
&lt;h3 id="about-alpscode">About AlpsCode&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hi there,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I originally started collecting notes about the new technologies I learned in my Dropbox folder.
When I realized that I start forgetting the ones that I do not use often, I have decided to practice with them.
So, the content of this blog is mostly about my forgotten notes being revived.
My aim is to keep every post short and concise, so that I can get what I am looking for when I need it.
Feel free to make a merge request on my &lt;a href="https://github.com/alpscode/website" target="_blank">Github repository&lt;/a> if you notice any errors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>