<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fantasy Premier League on AlpsCode</title><link>https://alpscode.com/tags/fantasy-premier-league/</link><description>Recent content in Fantasy Premier League on AlpsCode</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alpscode.com/tags/fantasy-premier-league/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Friendly Introduction to FPL Analytics</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/intro-to-fpl-analytics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/intro-to-fpl-analytics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>In this post, I tried to summarize the basics about using analytical tools and methods for Fantasy Premier League (FPL).
There is certainly more out there than I can cover, but I hope this will help newcomers to understand what analytics is and how it can help you enjoy FPL more.
Similar ideas can be applied to other fantasy sports games as well.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="part-1-seeing-beyond-the-curtain-underlying-stats">Part 1: Seeing Beyond the Curtain &lt;em>(Underlying Stats)&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You are sitting on your couch on a Saturday morning and suddenly remember that you have to transfer someone for your FPL team to beat your friend in &lt;em>that&lt;/em> mini-league.
You open the FPL app, sort players by total points so far and transfer the player on top that you do not own!
You are not 100% sure how the points system works in FPL, but after all, past performance should be an indicator of future performance, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflections from my first FPL season</title><link>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-reflections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://alpscode.com/blog/fpl-reflections/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you ask any Fantasy Premier League (FPL) player on Twitter about what word has been beaten to death last season, they&amp;rsquo;d likely respond with &amp;ldquo;optimal&amp;rdquo;.
I must admit that I played a part in starting or fuelling more than my fair share of these discussions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">There are optimal ways to play FPL.&lt;/p>&amp;mdash; Sertalp B. Çay (@sertalpbilal) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/sertalpbilal/status/1376578600854519808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 29, 2021&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8">&lt;/script>


&lt;p>It might come as a suprise to some that I had never heard of FPL before August of 2020, just a week before I went on vacation.
It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that my time off was spoiled (to a degree) after my dear colleague, Bas Belfi, challenged me in the upcoming FPL season with the aid of analytics.
Like any sane person, I spent most of my time after that reading through rules, reviewing academic papers, and taking notes from every guide I came across on Reddit.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>